# PARTH BHAVESH KUMAR BHATT

6084 Stanton Dr SW, Edmonton, Alberta, T6X 0Z4 | (705) 791-4648 parthkumar9@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/parthkumarbhatt

## **Objective**

I'm a full stack developer based in Edmonton with 2 years of experience in the software industry. My focus area for the past few years has been front-end development with NextJS, GatsbyJS, Redux but I'm also skilled in back-end development with Javascript, Node.js & C++. I am very quality-conscious and schedule-driven because I spent my early career years in Project Coordinator roles.

## **Technical Expertise**

- Programming Languages: C++, HTML, Swift, Solidity
- Scripting Languages & Libraries: PHP , JavaScript(ES6), React.js
- Frameworks: BootStrap 5, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Next Js, Gatsby Js,
- Database: MongoDB, MySql, FireStore
- Technologies: GitHub, Visual Studio, Firebase, Git for source control, Heroku
- CMS: Wordpress, Magento 2.4, Sanity.io, GraphQl

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Full-stack Developer / Project Manager

VebCommerce, Edmonton, Alberta Duration: July 2022 - Present

VebCommerce, a SAAS Web platform that allows you to integrate endless e-commerce platforms such as Amazon, eBay, Walmart, Magento, Shopify, Abe books, Big commerce, WooCommerce DHL, FedEx, UK Mail, Aramex, UPS, Canada Post, and many more. It will be a one-stop destination and a complete automation to all e-commerce platforms.

- Understand business's strategic direction, goals and objectives and deliver the program successfully along those goals and objectives.
- Responsible for reviewing Test Strategy and Test Plans with the team and to provide inputs on System Test, Functional Test, Stability Test, Security/Vulnerability Test, Performance Test, Disaster Recovery Test and Commissioning Test to finalize their involvement and assistance during these test phases.
- Responsible for generating and distributing Daily Status, Weekly Status and Exit Summary
  Reports
- Managing program/project scope and change control and escalating issues where necessary.
- Participate in **Agile** development of solutions based on acceptance criteria and design.
- Develop Technical Design Document based on User Stories provided by Product Owners & from requirement gathering meetings. Trace user stories to business objectives and the product vision throughout the sprint to ensure it's actually been delivered as imagined.
- **Communicate** continuously and effectively with external business partners and internal teams to articulate a project's comprehensive requirements.
- Identify gaps in **data requirements** between as-is and to be states. **Model** the data requirements to ensure that the data will support the new solution.

## **Web Developer / Project Coordinator**

Lofcart Alberta Ltd, Edmonton, Alberta

Duration: Jan 2021 - June 2022

Full-stack engineer in the team responsible for integrations and developer tools. We're in charge of defining and improving the User Experience and User Interface with Lofcart's platform as per business requirements.

- Redesigned existing website to include new features & improve user experience.
- Providing maintenance and support for **Magento 2** Migration, Upgradation, plugin development and updating security patches.
- Customized Lofcart's Admin panel with inherent features based on day to day use aswell as Business requirements
- Developed dynamic Landing pages using frameworks like NextJS and GatsbyJs with CMS tools like Sanity.io and GraphQl
- Involved in Application testing and used **GitHub** version control as a source repository
- Worked in an **Agile** environment and participated in several scrum meetings to discuss planning and development needed for the website.
- Analyze the project's **business requirements** into detailed functional specifications, user interface specifications, and general system requirements.
- Prepare and provide program/project status reports to the respective stakeholders.

### **Education**

**Computer Programmer, Diploma Program, Co-op** Georgian College, Barrie, ON September 2018- May 2021

#### Certifications

•	Smartphone Master technician	Oct 2021
•	SafeTALK	Sep 2019
•	Health And Awareness Training (Ministry of Labor)	Sep 2018